Enjoy Simple English 森崎ウィンです
毎週木曜日は2019年度に放送した
古典が語る西洋の知恵をお送りしています
ギリシャ神話Greek Mythから
西洋の表現や考えなどを学びます
今回はエコーです
では早速聞いてみましょう
many of you may know the word echo did you know that the word comes from a greek myth here is the story
echo was a beautiful nymph nymphs are spirits of nature echo enjoyed playing in the woods and artemis the goddess of hunting liked her very much artemis often said
I am going on a hunt. Come with me, Echo.
Echo was a good nymph, but she was not perfect.
She talked too much.
Echo always had the last word.
That means, when she talked with someone,
she always said something more after they finished talking.
One day, the goddess Hera
The wife of Zeus came to the woods to find her husband
Hera thought
I am sure Zeus is playing with nymphs
I must take him home
It was true
Zeus was in the woods
and he was having a good time with several nymphs
Echo thought
Hera is going to be really angry
The nymphs need time to escape
So Echo went to Hera and started talking with her.
Dear Hera, I can't believe you are here.
I am so happy.
Don't you think it is a lovely day?
Echo did not stop talking until all the nymphs escaped.
Hera found out about this and became very angry.
You tricked me with your words!
そのため、私はあなたから言葉を取り除きます
しかし、私は全てを取り除くことはできません
あなたは他の人々の言葉を言うことができますが、あなたは自分の言葉を言うことはできません
その時、エコーは他の人々の言葉を言うことができませんでした
その日、エコーはナーシシスを狙っていました
彼は素晴らしい若い男だった
エコはナーシシスに恋をした
彼を追いかけ始めた
彼女は彼に話したい
しかし彼女は自分の言葉を使えなかった
彼女はナーシシスと話すのを待っていた
数日後
ナーシシスは狩猟をして
友達から離れてしまった
彼は森の中を歩いて
声をかけた
Who's here? 誰が来てるの?
Echo said, エコーは
Here! ここだ!
Narcissus looked around, but he saw no one. ナーシシスは見つけたが、誰も見えなかった。
He continued, ナーシシスは続いて
Come! 来い!
And Echo answered, エコーは答えた
But Echo did not show herself. でもエコーは自分を見せなかった。
Then Narcissus said, ではナーシシスは言った
Let's join together! 一緒に一緒に行きましょう!
And Echo said the same words and went to Narcissus. エコーは同じ言葉を言ってナーシシスに行きました。
ナーシシスは驚きました。
私から逃げろ!
そして逃げました。
エコーはとても悲しかったです。
彼女は洞窟に住み始めました。
彼女はとても悲しかったです。
彼女の体は消えました。
エコーは石に変わりました。
しかし、彼女の声は残っていました。
彼女は今日、山の中にまだいます。
彼女は誰かが彼女に話してくれることを答えます。
ゼウスの浮気に怒った妻のヘラ
それでエコーから言葉を奪ってしまった
いやなんてすごい話ですね
あのエコーって音楽用語とかでもたくさん出てくるんで
よく聞くんですけど
まさかギリシャ神話から来ていた言葉だったとは興味深い
See you tomorrow!